Michael Berger

Summary

I'm an organized yet flexible web designer and game developer looking to use my skills to enrich the lives of others.

American Indian Science and Engineering Society (AISES) member since 2014.

Contact

mxb3145@rit.edu

(315) 761-1255

in michberger

Michael-A-Berger

Education

Rochester Institute of Technology Game Design and Development (GDD) Masters 2021

Computer Science (CS) Minor 2021 **Graduate GPA 3.85**

Skills

Web Development Software Prod. Multimedia

Javascript, Node, React, Typecript, JQuery, HTML5, CSS, PHP Git, MySQL, C++, C#, Java, .NET, Universal Modeling Language (UML) Unity, Adobe InDesign, Adobe Photoshop, GNU Image Manipulator (GIMP), Autodesk Maya, Blender, Adobe After Effects

Employment

University of Rochester Web Applications Project Assistant

Rochester, NY · June 2019 to Aug. 2019

- Created a portable website that utilized PHP and MySQL to match academic job criteria with their corresponding titles and IDs.
- Facilitated daily and weekly agile Scrum meetings to assess tasks using Jira management software.

Lenel Systems International Web Developer Co-op

Pittsford, NY · May 2018 to Aug. 2018

- WHO: Lenel is a worldwide provider of open-platform security solutions with integrated access control and video management
- WHAT: Programmed and patched features for a Typescript video player that is integrated into the OnGuard alarm and video monitoring services.

Parlec/Omega TMM Software Engineer Co-op

Fairport, NY · Jan. 2017 to Aug. 2017

- WHO: Omega TMM provides world class tool measuring machines (presetters) used in the machine tool
- WHAT: Developed features and bug fixes for the P7 machine shop tool measuring software using C# language and specialized development hardware kits.

Projects

Bit To Beat Aug. 2020 to Current

- A hybrid strategy-rhythm game. Responsible for team management, audio implementation, and level design.

July 2020 to Current

- A Javascript powered Discord bot specialized for rhythm game communities. Responsible for development and upkeep.

Feb. 2020 to Apr. 2020 Lantern Lights

- A physics-driven 2D platformer. Responsible for game conception, prototype implementation, platforming code, sound design, and minor level design.

All to Pieces: The Western Tabletop RPG

Sept. 2019 to Dec. 2019

- Responsible for InDesign formatting, rulebook publishing, and content creation.

Nov. 2018 to May 2019

- Independently developed a portable single page application library for tracking Japanese anime and manga collections using ECMAScript 6, Node, React, Express, and Gulp.

Anime Audio Visualizer

Feb. 2016 to Feb. 2016

- Created a configurable web browser audio visualizer that plays music over anime video clips and displays audio effects using Javascript, Canvas, and Font Awesome icons.

Activities

Tora-Con 2020 - Revenue Department Staff

Aug. 2018 to May 2019

Logistics Coordinator

- Responsible for managing physical layout and creating architectural diagram of both attendee registration and vendor areas.

RIT Anime Club - Eboard Member

Aug. 2019 to Apr. 2020

Club Librarian

- Responsible for cataloging club materials, managing member rentals, and organizing / cleaning the designated club space.